This isn't female empowerment. This is a last resort.
Students, teachers and housewives forced out of their homes, now training to fire a gun,
driven by the horror of their new reality and the little chance of leaving this country.
Why have you come to this training?
We've come to protect ourselves, our children, all we stand for against all we've seen, she says.
We've seen so much. It's an insane tragedy.
She says her nephew was killed by the RSF and that they abducted her niece.
The military is yet to restore their old lives.
Destroyed by the militia, the army itself once partnered and trained.
Now they're training these women to fight their shared enemy.
If this city falls to the RSF like so many others.
A country already on its knees is now being strangled by violence, hunger and disease.
Sudan strapped civilians are desperately holding on to life.
Only for each day of life to become harder to bear.
And of course the pandemic ever.
Okay.
Yeah.
And that's okay.
I know.
I'm out there.
I really won't be fun.
I wonder if this has been an example later.
I hope this has some luck places where I'm in my pocket and they're two folks.
I really won't do anything there.